One ring to rule them all.
The Lord of the Rings: The Fellowship of the Ring is a adventure,
fantasy, action film directed by Peter Jackson.
Young hobbit Frodo Baggins, after inheriting a mysterious ring from his uncle Bilbo, must leave
his home in order to keep it from falling into the hands of its evil creator.
Along the way, a fellowship is formed to protect the ringbearer and make
sure that the ring arrives at its final destination: Mt.
Doom, the only place where it can be destroyed.
Frodo, played by Elijah Wood.
Gandalf, played by Ian McKellen.
Aragorn, played by Viggo Mortensen.
Sam, played by Sean Astin.
Bilbo, played by Ian Holm.
Arwen, played by Liv Tyler.
The Lord of the Rings: The Fellowship of the Ring is a 2001 epic high fantasy adventure film
directed by Peter Jackson from a screenplay by Fran Walsh, Philippa Boyens, and Jackson.
It is based on J.
Tolkien's 1954 The Fellowship of the Ring, the first
volume of the novel The Lord of the Rings.
The film is the first instalment in The Lord of the Rings trilogy.
It features an ensemble cast including Elijah Wood, Ian McKellen, Liv Tyler, Viggo Mortensen, Sean Astin, Cate Blanchett, John
Rhys-Davies, Billy Boyd, Dominic Monaghan, Orlando Bloom, Christopher Lee, Hugo Weaving, Sean Bean, Ian Holm, and Andy Serkis.
Set in Middle-earth, the story tells of the Dark Lord Sauron, who seeks the
One Ring, which contains part of his might, to return to power.
The Ring has found its way to the young hobbit Frodo Baggins.
The fate of Middle-earth hangs in the balance as Frodo and eight companions (who form the eponymous Fellowship of the Ring)
begin their perilous journey to Mount Doom in the land of Mordor, the only place where the Ring can be destroyed.
The Fellowship of the Ring was financed and distributed by American studio New Line Cinema, but filmed and edited
entirely in Jackson's native New Zealand, concurrently with the other two parts of the trilogy.
It premiered on 10 December 2001 at the Odeon Leicester Square in London and was released
on 19 December in the United States and on 20 December in New Zealand.
The film was acclaimed by critics and audiences, who considered it a landmark in filmmaking and an achievement in the fantasy film genre, with
praise for the visual effects, performances, direction, screenplay, musical score, and faithfulness to the source material.
It grossed $868 million worldwide during its original theatrical run, making it the second-highest-grossing
film of 2001 and the fifth-highest-grossing film of all time at the time of its release.
Following subsequent reissues, it has grossed $896 million.
Like its successors, The Fellowship of the Ring is widely recognised as
one of the greatest and most influential films ever made.
The film received numerous accolades; at the 74th Academy Awards, it was nominated for thirteen awards, including Best
Picture, winning for Best Cinematography, Best Makeup, Best Original Score, and Best Visual Effects.
In 2007, the American Film Institute named it one of the 100 greatest American films in history, being both
the most recent film and the only film released in the 21st century to make it to the list.
In 2021, the film was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the
Library of Congress for being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant".
Two sequels, The Two Towers and The Return of the King,
followed in 2002 and 2003, respectively.
The film explores themes of based on novel or
book, elves, dwarf, magic, obsession.
The tone is intense.